

infoverload.ca

Berlin, Germany | Open to relocation or remote

(+49) 174 3886 933 | daisyts@gmx.com

Profile

An experienced developer and writer with an interest for the whole technology stack who is keen to be continually challenged. I am a curious generalist at heart who is able to pick up new concepts quickly. As a strong believer in documentation and knowledge sharing, I am adept at clear written communication. My focus has been in backend development with a strong interest in infrastructure and systems.

Competencies

Go, PHP, Ruby, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, SQL, Bash OOP, MVC, Symfony, WordPress Git, Mercurial, SVN MySQL, MongoDB
GNU/Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, Prometheus
Google App Engine, Heroku, CircleCl

Relevant Experience

Freelancer, Self-Employed - Remote

SPRING 2018 - WINTER 2018

 Perform ongoing consultative and development work ranging from website maintenance/upgrades, systems analysis, prototype creations, content generation, to business strategy and development

Technical Writer, Fixate IO - Remote

FALL 2017 - CURRENT

- Generate and edit in-depth technical content as a premier contributor (the highest rank in the Fixate network)
- Conduct market research and perform industry analysis
- Cover wide range of topics relating to software development, the DevOps landscape, testing strategies, etc

Open-Source Contributor - Remote

FALL 2017 - CURRENT

- Ongoing contributions to Prometheus, a systems monitoring toolkit written in Golang: add new default metric
 go_info to Go client library; document config options; add new features to command line utility; create
 custom node exporter for BME280 module
- Participation in Kubernetes Release Team (shadowing)

Community Coach, Rails Girls Berlin - Berlin, Germany

FALL 2017 - WINTER 2018

- Mentor and encourage people who identify as women with no programming experience to learn the full
 programming stack and gain practical experience by building their own Ruby on Rails application in a
 safe and welcoming environment
- Guide mentees with installation and taught fundamentals of programming

Backend Developer, Project A Services GmbH - Berlin, Germany

- **SPRING 2017 SUMMER 2017**
- Assisted backend development team on various venture projects using Symfony and PHP in a microservice architecture
- Analyzed existing prototype applications, refactored them and added features, following the company's best practices and software development principles

Full Stack Developer, eKomi Ltd - Berlin, Germany

SPRING 2014 - SUMMER 2015

- Supported IT team with both frontend and backend development and debugging tasks on a large codebase
- Performed both client-facing work (designing customized, responsive review pages for clients) and internal tooling for the rest of the team

Software Developer, GrantStream Inc - Oakville, Canada

SPRING 2011 - FALL 2012

- Responsible for a variety of development projects in grant management software including maintenance of PHP applications and MS SQL Server and MySQL databases
- Configured UI of customized Web applications with PHP, MSSQL, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS

Education

Certificate in Project Management - University of Toronto

FALL 2010 - SPRING 2011

Bachelor of Arts - University of Western Ontario

FALL 2004 - FALL 2009

• Double Major in Computer Science and Media Studies

Exchange Program - Université Stendhal

WINTER 2008 - SUMMER 2008

• Participation in academic exchange program in Grenoble (France) through the University of Western Ontario

Continuing Education

Bill Kennedy's Ultimate Go Workshop

2018

• A weekend course designed to provide an intensive idiomatic view of Go

Women Techmakers - JavaScript Crash Course

2017 - 2018

- A 12-week lecture course designed to expose participants to multiple levels of the software development stack
- Introductions to Node.js, Vue.js, MongoDB, Unit Testing, CI/CD, Design Patterns, Bridging APIs, and more

Volkshochschule Berlin - Deutsch als Fremdsprache

2015 - 2016

• Completed courses up to level B1.1

Personal Projects

Observability in the Kitchen

- explores relationship between sourdough cultures, humidity, and temperature to improve breadmaking
- custom exporters running on Raspberry Pis exports metrics from digital sensors which is scraped and stored by monitoring server; data used to make dashboards for analysis and to create appropriate alerts
- leverages Raspberry Pis, Bosch BME280 sensors, Prometheus, Grafana, Go, sourdough starters

Wortschatz Logger

- web application aimed at helping people familiarize themselves with German articles
- includes personal user accounts that allows word tracking/categorizing and interactive quizzes
- built with PHP Laravel framework (version 5.3), PostgreSQL, JavaScript, jQuery, SASS

Der Die Das Game

- HTML5 browser game that allows player to control a sprite-generated character to hit Lebkuchen hearts containing German words that correspond correctly to the German article displayed for each round
- built with the Phaser game framework (version 2.6.2) and JavaScript

Talks

Baby Steps to Open-Source Contribution

PromCon 2018

A lightning talk that discusses how underrepresented folks in technology can be involved with open-source software and what individuals and companies can do to help increase diverse contributions

Improve Your Bread-making Skills with Open-Source Monitoring

DACHFest 2018, BangBangCon West 2019

A lightning talk about my project that combines my use of open-source systems monitoring tools and my interest in making the perfect sourdough bread